Hoffman Family Papers
© 2006 University of Connecticut
- Series V: Newspaper and Periodical Clippings, undated, 1936-1997
  - News, 1978 January - August, [1. Claudia Cohen (editor), "Abbie's back," unknown, comments on the Bring Abbie Home Committee; 2. Mark Rowland, "Local Color: Abbie Road," unknown, reflections on the Bring Abbie Home Committee event; 3. Howard Smith, "Abbie: Unhappy Wanderer," unknown, reflections on the Bring Abbie Home Committee event; 4. unknown, "Abbie lookalikes plannin' a party," unknown, Bring Abbie Home Committee benefit concert; 5. Abbie Hoffman, "Fugitive on the Town," The Village Voice, discussion of the underground lifestyle; 6. South Middlesex News, February 9th, 1978; 7. Bob Greene, "Judge Hoffman of Chicago 7 Fame Looks Back at 82," The Evening Gazette, Judge Hoffman reflects on his career as a judge; 8. Sydney H. Schanberg, "Sox Fan Finally Confesses," The Evening Gazette, editorial about the Red Sox; 9. Jeff Jarvis, "Rock revolt," San Francisco Examiner, riot at rock concert in USSR; 10. James A. Gourgouras, "Night for Abbie Hoffman Is Planned," The Evening Gazette, Bring Abbie Home Committee event; 11. Howard Smith, "Bring Abbie Back Update," unknown, reflections on the event; 12. Yipster Times, June 1978; 13. Robert R. Bliss, "Fifth Ave.: a Long Way From Green Street," The Evening Gazette, interviews with A. Richard Golub; 14. Yipster Times, August 1978; 15. Jack Tubert, "Benefit to 'Bring Abbie Hoffman Home'," unknown, reflections on the Bring Abbie Home Committee concert (two copies); 16. Bob Greene, "'68 Convention Trivia Quiz," The Evening Gazette, quiz on the Chicago 7 trial; 17. Lee M. Hammel, "Prospect House to Give Abbie Hoffman Plaque," Worcester Telegram, Hoffman to reccieve plaque at the Prospect House (two copies); 18. Worcester Telegram, Thursday August 24th, 1978, Local News.] (Box 8:185)
  - News, 1978 September - December, [1. Charles P. Pierce, "Abbie! Calling a native son home," Worcester, editorial in favor of Hoffman returning to Worcester; 2. Worcester September 1978; 3. Peter Biskind, "Return of the Native," Crawdoodah Gazette, editorial in favor of Hoffman returning to Worcester; 4. David Newman, "The Abbie Hoffman Bash," New York Gazette, Bring Abbie Home Committee benefit concert; 5. Howard Smith and Cathy Cox, "Abbie Hoffman, Critic at Large," The Village Voice, popular culture and Hoffman; 6. unknown, "No, the Yippie Leader of the 1960s Is Not Writing Commercials on Madison Avenue," unknown, comments on a movie dramatization of Hoffman's life; 7. Forum Magazine, "A Very Personal Interview with Abbie Hoffman," Forum Magazine, interview with Hoffman concerning principally the underground but also his life in general; 8. Associated Press, "Abbie Hoffman, Wanted by FBI, Believed in Hollywood for Film," unknown, Hoffman believed to be staring in a movement about his life (two copies); 9. unknown, "Fugitive Abbie Hoffman Surfaces in L.A.: Q&A," Los Angeles Examiner, interview concerning upcoming film and life in the underground; 10. Abe Peck, "Abbie in Chicago: 'Good to be home'," The Chicago Sun-Times, reflections on life in the underground and how it changed his life.] (Box 8:186)
  - News, 1979, [1. Frank Connolly, "Abbie to publish a book," unknown, Hoffman is in the process of writing his autobiography Soon to Be A Motion Picture; 2. Abe Peck, "Abbie Hoffman Plans His Autobiography," Phoenix Sun Times, Hoffman is in the process of writing his autobiography Soon to Be A Motion Picture; 3. Jack Anderson, "Fugitive Abbie Hoffman 'It's Very, Very, Hard'," The Miami Herald, summary of Hoffman's life along with an interview on how painful it is to be seperated from his children; 4. Gerri (sic) Rubin, "Three Faces of Abbie," Feature, letter to the editor about Hoffman's writing; 5. Abbie Hoffman, "Castro Redirected," New York Times, letter to the editor about the Red Sox and Fidel Castro; 6. Clyde Haberman and Albin Krebs, "Tales of Hoffman Are Taped for Radio Network," New York Times, Hoffman gives an interview to WNEW FM; 7. Bud Collins, "Reminiscence," Sports Illustrated, reflections on Hoffman's successes on the Brandeis tennis team; 8. William M. Kunstler and Stewart E. Albert, "The Great Conspiracy Trial of '69," The Nation, summary of the Chicago 7 trial and post-trial developments; 9. Jack Martin, "Activist Abbie tosses a bash, but his pals get stuck with the bill," unknown, 40th birthday party for Hoffman; 10. Dan Kaplan, "Abbie!," unknown, interview with Hoffman focusing on his views on life rather than politics; 11. Jack Tubert, "Say, Dear, Wasn't That Abbie Hoffman?," unknown, details of Hoffman's life underground along with his new views on politics; 12. unknown, "Abbie Hoffman Pays a Call at the Kennedy Library and Basks in his Bamboozling of the Feds," People, summary of recent Hoffman interviews; 13. Bruce McCabe, "Abbie Hoffman in Boston? You bet your life!," The Boston Globe, interview with Hoffman concerning how he would like to return to Worcester; 14. Danny Schechter, "Remember Abbie Hoffman?," The Real Paper, interview with Hoffman about the anonymity of the underground; 15. Abbie Hoffman, "'Say something good about the '70s'," Daily News, Hoffman picks his favorite movies and records from the 1970s.] (Box 8:186A)
  - News, 1980, [1. Theodore Sturgeon, "Soon to Be a Major Motion Picture," Hustler, review of Hoffman's autobiography; 2. Morris Dickstein, "Wild Child of the Media," New York Times, review of Hoffman's autobiography (two copies); 3. Bob Greene, "'This Is Abbie' - at 43," unknown, interview with Hoffman about his autobiography (two copies); 4. United Press International, "Living on the Run Isn't All Adventure," unknown, summary of major events while underground; 5. unknown, "Abbie Hoffman's new book gets competition for title," unknown, concern that the title of the book will not work when it is made into a film; 6. David J. Blum, "Now Playing at a Television Near You," Wall Street Journal, review of Hoffman's autobiography; 7. Melvin Maddock, "Abbie: After outrage, what?," unknown; review of Hoffman's autobiography; 8. Helen Dudar, "Fugitive Abbie Hoffman: The Underground Author," Calender, review of Hoffman's autobiography; 9. Tom Zito, "The Great January Cover-Up; Picking the Moon of the Year; The Great January Cover-Up; Editorial Lunacy? Three Times, By Jove," Style, collection of thoughts on the transition to the 1980s; 10. Leonore Fleischer, unknown, Washington Post, distribution of Hoffman's autobiography; 11. William Plummer, "Dear Abbie," TWA Ambassador, review of Hoffman's autobiography; 12. Rudy Maxa, "Hoffman: Soon to Be a Major Motion Picture," Washington Post Magazine, review of Hoffman's autobiography; 13. Paul L. Berman, "Yippie Redux," Village Voice, review of Hoffman's autobiography and reflections on his life; 14. Richard Cohen, "A 12-Year-Old Discovers Friends, Bike, Freedom," The Wasington Post, story on a Russian boy who emigrates to the United States; 15.] (Box 8:187)
  - News, 1981, [1. unknown, "Abbie struggling through tough times," Soho News, Hoffman's trouble with the media and the law; 2. Evelyn Sucher, unknown, Jewish Student Press Service, Hoffman comments on Jewish opposition to Israeli policies; 3. unknown, "Remember them?," Worcester Sunday Telegram, famous faces of Worcester, including Hoffman's father; 4. Claudia Cohen and Cyndi Stivers, "Abbie Hoffman's letters of transit," Daily News, celebrities and writers argue on behalf of Hoffman; 5. Greg Reasor, "Abbie Hoffman: the media manipulator," Daily Law Bulletin, review of Soon to be a Major Motion Picture; 6. Lewis H. Lapham, "Shooting Stars," comments on celebrity, with a section on Hoffman; 7. Peggy Constantine, "A Stolen Book That's Still Hot," Newsday, increasing interest in Steal This Book; 8. Ned Goldreyer, "Cousin Abbie Fires 'Em Up," unknown, 5,000 people attend Hoffman's talk at Stony Brook (two copies); 9. n/a, "Excerpts From White House Tape of a Nixon-Halderman Talk in May 1971," New York Times; discussions of illegal activity 10. n/a, "Criminals and Writers," New York Times Book Review, letters concerning The Strange Case of the Writer and the Criminal; 11. Leah Lamson, "Booking It: Show promoter learned through trial and error," Time Out, Jack Hoffman enters the concert booking business to turn Worcester into the mecca of rock 'n roll; 12. n/a, "Foods for Chanukah," The Jewish Chornicle-Leader, recipies.] (Box 8:188)
  - News, 1982, [1. Associated Press, "Nofziger is found guilty," unknown, Reagan aide found guilty of illegal lobbying; 2. Mark Samuels, "Abbie Hoffman: Steal this Interview," OIU, interview with Hoffman concerning his recent activities and past; 3. C.H. 'Max' Freedman, "Abbie Hoffman: humanity exploiter extraordinaire," The News World, Hoffman is accused of corrupting America by promoting drug use; 4. Abbie Hoffman, "Which 'Ism' is It?," The Nation, letter to the editor on the meaning of 'socialism'; 5. n/a, n/a, Middlesex News, photo with caption describing Hoffman's appearance at Clark University; 6. Scott Mackay, "Hoffman Rekindles Radical Spirit," The Burlington Free Press, Hoffman speaks at University of Vermont; 7. George Basler, "Hoffman at SUNY," The Evening Press, Hoffman speaks at Binghamton University; 8. Evelyn Sucher, unknown, Jewish Student Press Service, Hoffman comments on Jewish opposition to Israeli policies (reprint); 9. Joe Cassidy, "Liddy Fizzles in Great Debate," unknown, Hoffman and Liddy debate the 60s and the 80s (two copies); 10. Thomas J. Martello, "Abbie Back in Islands, Pledges N-Waste Fight," Watertown Daily Times, Hoffman returns to the Thousand Islands to continue his activism; 11. James L. Kerwin, "Ex-radical Hoffman plugs for group to save lakes," unknown, Hoffman returns to the Thousand Islands to continue his activism; 12. Tom Searls, "Grassroots activism has replaced radicalism of the 60's, Hoffman says," Dominion-Post, Hoffman discusses activism at West Virginia University.] (Box 8:189)
  - News, 1983, [1. Terrie Clifford, "Democracy Demands Dissent, OU Students Told," unknown, Hoffman speaks at Oklahoma University; 2. Michael Venture, "What is Low Power Television, And How Will It Change Your Whole Life?: An Interview with Jeffrey Nightbyrd," L.A. Weekly, interview with Nightbyrd about his commerical endeavours; 3. Harvey Wasserman, "A New Age Interview," New Age, interview with Hoffman on the differences and parallels between the 60's and today (two copies);4. Evan Katz, "Abbie Hoffman to speak at OU Thursday; last speech cancelled from fear of arrest," The Oklahoma Daily, Hoffman to speak at Oklahoma University; 5. Madeline Patton, "Shake 'em up: Middle age, not middle class, overtakes Abbie Hoffman," reflections on the changes in Hoffman's political approach; 6. Evan Katz, "Once-banned Hoffman to speak here again," Oklahoma Daily, Hoffman to speak at Oklahoma University; 7. Wilda Wahpepah and Evan Katz, "Hoffman ignites standing-room-only crowd," The Oklahoma Daily, Hoffman speaks at Oklahoma University (two copies); 8. Steve Ray Linam, "Hoffman urges crowd to reject complacency," The Transcript, Hoffman sepaks at Oklahoma University; 9. unknown, "Abbie Hoffman to Speak May 2nd," The Fitchburg State Strobe, Hoffman to speak at Fitchburg State; 10. Dr. Paul Donohue, "Blood Pressure Drugs Often Need Some Adjustment," The Evening Gazette, article on health concerns.] (Box 8:190)
  - News, 1984, [1. n/a, n/a, n/a, assorted United Press International story abstracts, two involving Hoffman's recent speaking tours; 2. Michael H. Seitz, "The Way We Were," The Progressive, review of film soundtrack in which Hoffman's name is mentioned in passing.] (Box 8:191)
  - News, 1985, [1. David Corn, "The Abbie & Jerry Show," Mother Jones, Hoffman and Rubin go on a debate tour (two copies); 2. n/a, n/a, n/a, United Press International story abstract on Hoffman's trip to Nicaragua; 3. James Dempsey, "A Punchy History Of the 1960s," unknown, editorial on the history of the Worcester Punch (two copies); 4. Jeffrey Nightbyrd, "On LPTV, Entreprenuers Have Starring Roles," Inc., Nightbyrd starts up low power television; 5. Benny Avni, "Interview With Abbie Hoffman," Tikkun, Hoffman comments on Israel and Judaism (two copies).] (Box 8:192)
  - News, 1986, [1. n/a, n/a, n/a, press release for the Urine Defense Fund; 2. Edward M. Sills, "Austin man a whiz in urine business," San Antonio Light, Nightbyrd develops a product to mask drugs in urine; 3. unknown, "CIA spying on networks?," unknown, CIA asks 60 Minutes not to air a report four days before it is to be aired; 4. unknown, unknown, Bonus Book, Hoffman's mother discusses her son; 5. Jon Laitin, "Boogying to the Bank," New Business, Nightbyrd finds success in LPTV; 6. unknown, "Hoffman plays the club circuit," unknown, Hoffman begins club tours with political commentary (two copies); 7. Michael James, "CIA protest at UM ends in arrests, legal moves," unknown, Hoffman involved in building occupation at UMass; 8. Deborah McDermott, "UMass students say they'll continue protest," Daily Hampshire Gazette, UMass students continue CIA protest in the face of legal battles; 9. Associated Press, "Hoffman, 58 Others Arrested in Protest," unknown, arrests at building occupation at UMass involving Hoffman; 10. Jeff Shero, "Urine the USA," The Austin Chronicle, Shero interviews Nightbyrd about his formula to mask contaminated urine; 11. George Hackett, Peter McKillop, and Richard Sandza, "The Amy and Abbie Brigade," Newsweek, Hoffman and Amy Carter, daughter of Jimmy Carter, involved in anti-CIA demonstrations at UMass; 12. David Hanners, "Powdered urine seen as million-dollar idea,"unknown, piece on Nightbyrd's powdered urine business; 13. Morton H. Halperin, "Tighten the Law on Covert Operations," New York Times, editorial against CIA intervention in Central America.] (Box 8:193)
  - News, 1987 January - March, [1. Jim Henderson, "Deduction's cut but IRAs still OK," USA Today, information on tax filing; 2. Jennifer Lin, "Oct. crash hit more than just stock business," unknown, effect of the stock market crash on the market as a whole; 3. Marian Sandmaier, "The First Lady Was an Addict," The New York Times Book Review, review of Betty Ford's autobiography "Betty"; 4. unknown, "Court records show Blue failed drug tests in 1986," USA Today, Giants pitcher Vida Blue tested positive for cocaine during the 1986 season; 5. Reginald Stuart, "U.S. Relieves Aide Who Ran Drug Tests in Amtrak Crash," New York Times, FAA investigates an employee around misconduct allegations; 6. Sam Meddis, "Drug war termed 'sad state of affairs'," USA Today, problems with the War on Drugs; 7. unknown, unknown, Worcester Telegram, Hoffman and Carter found innocent in trial; 8. Neil Roland, "Possible Iran-contra illegalities are listed," Philadelphia Inquirer, allegations in the Iran-Contra scandal; 9. William K. Stevens, "Reflection And Hijinks At Festival," New York Times, Philadelphia conference on the present day state of the fifty states; 10. Fred Bernstein, "Amy Carter and Abbie Hoffman Win Acquittal, But They Want to Keep the C.I.A. on Trial," unknown, Hoffman and Carter discuss the role of C.I.A. in human rights abuses; 11. n/a, n/a, The Evening Gazette, editorial pieces on Iran-Contra and the Hoffman and Carter case; 12. Mathea Falco, "Reagan's Drug Policy: A Bust," New York Times, editorial on the failure of Reagan's drug policies; 13. Robert Pear, "Customs Retreating on Drug Testing," New York Times, US Customs changes policy on drug testing; 14. Diane Ackerman, "He Put Words In Our Mouths," Parade Magazine, reflections on Noah Webster; 15. Matthew L. Wald, "Hoffman: A Radical In All Ages," New York Times, reflections on the life of Abbie Hoffman; 16. n/a, n/a, New York Times, advertisement from Reader's Digest "We can win the cocaine war - if 'we' includes you"; 17. Bernard Weinraub, "The Matter of Money And Fighting Drugs," New York Times, President Reagan rejects further spending on drug rehabilitation (two copies); 18. Peter Kerr, "Crack Addiction: The Tragic Toll on Women and Their Children," New York Times, report on the rising rates of crack usage by women in poor neighborhoods; 19. n/a, n/a, In These Times, letter to the editor page; 20. Associated Press, "Miss Carter to testy in protest trial," unknown, Carter testifies in anti-C.I.A. rally trial; 21. unknown, "Workers Banned Over Drugs," unknown, five workers are fired after testing positive for drugs; 22. n/a, "I'm back, I'm clean, I love what I'm doing," USA Today, interview with Dennis Hopper; 23. Thomas E. Ricks and Martha Brannigan, "Drug lawyer's dream?," Wall Street Journal, trial of major drug dealer; 24. unknown, "Drug rule exposed," unknown, critical comment on the enforcement of drug laws; 25. Reuters, "Drug Testing on Rails Praised as a Deterrent," New York Times, drug testing serves as a deterrent; 26. Associated Press, "Drug-testing rules issued for federal employees," The Morning Union, new drug regulations for federal employees; 27. Peter Kerr, "High-School Marijuana Use Still Declining U.S. Servey Shows," New York Times, reduction in marjiuana use amongst high school students; 28. Linda Greenhouse, "Redrawing Battle Lines On Aid to the Contras," New York Times, Congressional debate over the Iran-Contra issue; 29. Michael R. Gordon, "On Making a Better Warhead," New York Times, Washington believes that Moscow has developed more sophisticated warheads; 30. n/a, "Exerpts From Opinion and Dissent in Alabama Affirmative Action Decision," New York Times, ruling in federal affirmative action case; 31. Pennslyvannia Gazette, the official alumni magazine of University of Pennslyvannia, Vol. 85, No. 5, March 1987; 32. Associated Press, "Senate Unit Backs Drug Tests For Transportation Workers," New York Times, federal agencies implement new drug tests; 33. unknown, unknown, unknown, public interest story on the Dukakis family; 34. n/a, n/a, New York Times, advertisement from Reader's Digest "How non-smokers can kick the habit"; 35. unknown, "Employers Battling Drug Use on the Job," New York Times, companies are using private firms for drug testing; 36. Harry Levine and Craig Reinarman, "What's Behind 'Jar Wars'," The Nation, the invasiveness and mistakes in federal drug testing.] (Box 8:194)
  - News, 1987 April - December, [1. Richard Levine, "Rules Eased On Ordering Drug Tests," New York Times, changes in the New York MTA drug testing; 2. n/a "It's still trespassing," Daily Hampshire Gazette, editorial arguing that Hoffman and Carter are guilty regardless of the political nature of the protest; 3. Associated Press, "Hoffman, Amy Carter and others set to defend anti-CIA conduct," The Evening Gazette, Hoffman and Carter go to trial for trespassing; 4. Deborah McDermott, "Jury selection continues," The Daily Hampshire, jury selection for the Hoffman and Carter anti-CIA protest case; 5. Deborah McDermott, "Trial publicity is an ordeal," The Daily Hampshire, impact of the life on Carter's life; 6. Associated Press, "Abbie Hoffman starting to worry about paying for cost of his trial," unknown, proceedings of the trial; 7. Associated Press, "High on cocaine: Seizures, disturbances," Daily Hampshire Gazette, report on cocaine usage; 8. Deborah McDermott, "Jury finally chosen for trial of CIA protestors," Daily Hampshire Gazette, jury selection completed; 9. Deborah McDermott and Brenda Elliot, "Hoffman, Carter witnesses claim CIA committed crimes," Daily Hampshire Gazette, trial proceedings; 10. Associated Press, "Carter trial witnesses call CIA the criminal," The Evening Gazette, trial proceedings; 11. Peter Shinkle and Dennis Bernstein, "U.S. hires drug dealer to deal humanitarian aid," Guardian, State Department employee engaged in drug dealing for the United States government; 12. Brenda Elliot, "Ellsberg testifies in anti-CIA trial," Daily Hampshire Gazette, trial proceedings; 13. Associated Press, "It's Amy's turn to take the stand today in CIA case," unknown, Carter to take the stand; 14. Paul Katzeff, "Boston firms are slow to join drug-test trend," Boston Herald, Boston companies buck national trend of drug testing; 15. unknown, "(illegible) testifies," Daily Hampshire Gazette, Carter testifies on her role in the anti-CIA protests; 16. Deborah McDermott, "Former attorney general testifies; trial will end tomorrow," Daily Hampshire Gazette, trial proceedings; 17. Deborah McDermott, "Jury will consider necessity defense," Daily Hampshire Gazette, jury deliberations and trial conclusion; 18. Deborah McDermott, "Freeing protestors seen as statement against CIA," Daily Hampshire Gazette, Hoffman and Carter found innocent; 19. Associated Press, "A proud father," Daily Hampshire Gazette, former President Carter approves of daughter's activism; 20. Paul Oh, "Jurors discuss protestors: 'They did it for a reason'," Daily Hampshire Gazette, jurors justify the actions of Hoffman and Carter on political grounds; 21. Deborah McDermott, "The CIA trial verdict," Daily Hampshire Gazette, analysis of the trial; 22. Francis X. Clines, "Laying Down the Law At the Cannabis Café'," New York Times, Dutch police crack down on drug use in Amsterdam; 23. Kenneth B. Noble, "U.S. Appeals Courts, in Four Cases, Back Drug Tests on Public Workers," New York Times, court upholds the legality of workers; 24. unknown, "On Trial: Cheers and Jeers for Amy Carter," Newsweek, reflections on Carter and the spectacle of the trial; 25. Joseph Nocera, "Amy's Day," unknown, reflections on Carter's activism; 26. John Leonard, "Agit Props," unknown, review of movie on the 1960s; 27. Mary McGrory, "Amy and Abbie: the miniseries," unknown, editorial on the anti-CIA trespassing trial; 28. Joanna Zikos, "Prospect House guided by a dream," The Evening Gazette, report on the history of the Prospect House; 29. Chris Pope, "Prospect House Renews Commitment," Worcester Telegram, report on the history of the Prospect House; 30. Nightfall June 1987; 31. A Farewell to the Praire Home Companion Summer 1987; 32. n/a, n/a, Guardian, section on Nicaragua; 33. n/a, n/a, In These Times, articles: "The Second American Revolution", editorial page, and "Bush's role in the CIA"; 34. Bob Waite, "Abbie Hoffman: Buck's Dollar A Year Dissident," Delaware Valley Magazine, interview with Hoffman about his past and current activities; 35. Susan Brink, "Abbie's road: Hoffman hits on new cause," Boston Herald, Hoffman targets drug testing as his new cause; 36. Andrew Kopkind, "God's on His Side," The Nation, interview with Pat Robertson on how Reagan sold out the conservative movement by appointing too many moderates; 37. Peter Kerr, "U.S. Drug 'Crusade' Is Seen as Undermining Itself," New York Times, poor planning and coordination has hampered the anti-drug crusade; 38. n/a, n/a, n/a, collection of articles on Nicaragua from various sources; 39. Tom Perry, "Activist from '60s gives stirring talk at Rutgers," Courier News, reflections on Hoffman's lecture at Rutgers.] (Box 8:195)